Vedran Arnautovic

Director of Product Design, Zendesk

527 Brunswick Street Fitzroy North VIC 3068

phone 0434 490 076 web vedran.io email hello@vedran.io twitter @vedranio

I'm a design leader focused on nurturing individual designers and growing design teams that deliver customer value through powerful enterprise grade SaaS software.

Over the last five years, I've defined what Admin Experience at Zendesk is, and built and led a global team of designers responsible for evolving it. My team is responsible for core admin features and a "satellite" design system that enables the design of Zendesk Answer Bot, Messaging, Integrations, Omnichannel Routing, and many other flagship features.

Experience

Zendesk (five years)

Sep 2021 – present

Director, Product Design

- Providing strategic leadership and design direction on high-impact product areas across a global team of product and content designers
- Building a design culture focused on excellence of craft, business impact, practitioner growth, and inclusivity
- Nurturing career growth of a team of designers, with four promotions in the last two years, and zero attrition across my team

Mar 2021 - Sep 2021

Senior Manager, Product Design

- · Grew the Admin Experience design team from four to seven designers
- Built the first "satelite" design system at Zendesk, enabling greater feature consistency and shorter time to value

Jan 2020 - Mar 2021

Manager, Product Design

- Put together a successful business case for the Admin Experience design team and grew the team to four product designers
- Established critique and collaboration practices for a global team of product and content designers

Jul 2018 - Jan 2020

Lead Product Designer

- Led design for Zendesk Admin Centre
- · Defined what Admin Experience at Zendesk is, with buy-in from exec leadership
- Made multiple contributions to the Zendesk design system

Nov 2017 – Jul 2018

Senior Product Designer

- · Initiated design of Zendesk's new Admin Centre
- Conducted foundational research on Zendesk admins which is referenced and used five years on

SEEK

Jan 2014 - Nov 2017

Senior UX Designer

- · Worked with agile teams developing features for SEEK's career portal
- Collaborated with senior leaders to define the future vision for the portfolio of job advertiser products
- Kicked off SEEK's first design system using Axure RP and contributed multiple components

Freelance

Oct 2016 - Oct 2017

SEEK sabbatical leave spent travelling in Europe

Lead UX designer

- · Designed a reception sign in iPad app for Gymsales, including UI animation
- Facilitated design workshops for Rubicon and their Dutch clients (online education)
- · Coached Kolektiv (online job portal organisation) in usability testing and analysis

SMS

Sep 2010 - Jan 2014

Consultant (UX designer and BA)

- Designed customer journeys and UI for online lending products (NAB)
- Worked on a fuel vehicle scheduling system as an Interface Designer and BA (BP)

Leica

Feb 2009 – Sep 2010 Melbourne

System Design Engineer & BA

- · Designed the UI for medical device software
- Performed usability testing of medical device service software with internal production line engineers

Leica

Feb 2007 – Feb 2009 London

System Design Engineer

A career shaping opportunity allowed me to spend two years in Europe researching how Leica's clients — pathology labs — and support teams interacted with our instruments, and to use those findings to design better solutions for them

Vision BioSystems

Jan 2004 - Feb 2007

Software Engineer

I started out very technical, developing software for medical devices. Working in an organisation with no designers created a window of opportunity to start designing and to test software with users.

Education

Univ. of Melbourne

1999 - 2004

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science

Bachelor's degree, Mechatronics

Viewbank College

Graduated 1998

VCE ENTER score 98.75